<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Notes of zf2timo</title>
        <link></link>
        <description>RSS feed for Notes of zf2timo</description>
        <atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <item>
                <title>Zend MVC Expressive Bridge</title>
                <description><![CDATA[<p>In this blog post, i'd like to promote my zf-mvc-expressive-bridge Module.</p>

<h2>Reason</h2>

<p>For a private Project i needed the Zend\InputFilter to validate all of the User Input. While
figuring out, how to integrate zend PluginManager into a Expressive application, i realized it
isn't easy as expected.</p>

<p>After a Short Chat with Matthew, it was clear: I have to create Factories by myself to initialize
the PluginManager as the "default" Factories stay in the Zend\MVC Package.</p>

<p>So i thought there a more Projects, which encounter the same Problem. And the idea of zf-mvc-expressive-bridge was born.</p>

<h2>Realisation</h2>

<p>As noted, the Problem are the Factories laying in the Zend\MVC Package. Of course, i could just install this Package
and use only the needed Factories.
But my application is build with Zend Expressive and not Zend MVC so its don't feels right.</p>

<p>Because the needed Factories already exists, this Package only extracts the PluginManager Factories from Zend\MVC
Package. That's it. So all unused classes arn't downloaded.</p>

<h2>Lifetime</h2>

<p>In the Chat with Matthew, he noted, that the Problem with the Factories are known and the Solution is on the todo list.
When the Task is done, the zf-mvc-expressive-bridge is deprecated immediately and the use should switch to Factories
provided by the Package (e.g. Zend\InputFilter).</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Hopefully with the zf-mvc-expressive-bridge Package i helped someone and saved some work.</p>
]]></description>
                <link>/2016/03/29/zend-mvc-expressive-bridge</link>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <guid>/2016/03/29/zend-mvc-expressive-bridge</guid>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>
